VISHNU VISWANATH

1609 W Ayres Avenue, Peoria, IL +13095502311 vviswanath@mail.bradley.edu http://vishnuviswanath.com https://github.com/soniclavier http://stackoverflow.com/users/864624 https://www.linkedin.com/in/vishnuviswanath25

SUMMARY: Graduate student currently pursuing MS in Computer Science with concentration in Data Analytics. Consistent high performer and results-oriented professional with **4.5 years** of work experience in **Java** and **Big Data** technologies.

SKILLS:

- Java, Python, Scala, C#
- Apache Spark, Storm, Kafka, Flume, SOLR, Pig, Oozie, Sqoop
- MonogDB, Hive, Hbase
- Spark ML, Numpy, Scipy, R, Graphlab, Weka, Octave
- J2EE, JSP, SOAP, REST, SOA, IBM MB, MQ, WPS

- Hibernate, Spring, Struts, Dozer
- Oracle 11g, MSSQL 2012, MySQL
- Apache Tomcat, WAS 6.1,
- Javascript, CSS, JQuery, Jekyll
- Unix, Windows, OSX

EDUCATION:

Master of Science: Computer Science; BRADLEY UNIVERSITY, Peoria, IL

08/2015 to Current

- Graduate Research assistant, working for Caterpillar Inc. research on supply chain network resilience modeling and critical node prediction.
- o CGPA 4.0/4.0, Awarded Graduate Assistantship
- Bachelor of Technology: Computer Science; CUSAT, Kerala, India

09/2006 to 04/2010

- Percentage 68.15, converted CGPA 7.2/10
- MOOCs/Certifications

0	Deep Learning, (Google, Udacity)	Ongoing
0	Machine Learning: Classification (UW, Coursera specialization)	Ongoing
0	Machine Learning: Regression, (UW, Coursera specialization)	Jan, 2015
0	Machine Learning Foundations, (UW, Coursera specialization)	Dec,2015
0	Machine Learning, Andrew Ng (Coursera)	Dec,2014
0	M101P: MonogDB for developers(MongoDB)	Nov,2013
0	Data Mining with Weka (University of Waikato)	Oct,2013
0	Introduction to Data Science, (University of Washington, Coursera)	Jun,2013
0	Algorithm Design and Analysis, (Stanford University, Coursera)	Mar,2013

WORK HISTORY:

Sr. Developer BigData, AIG Data Services Pvt Ltd.

11/2014 to 07/2015

- Lead developer of Hadoop based end-to-end system for Network analysis which is used for identifying security threats. The system had to handle high velocity of incoming data of 2 million records/minute – used Apache Flume, Oozie, Pig, SOLR, J2EE, Web Service and Mahout.
- Received Leadership Spot Award for my contributions towards this project.
- Commendation received from process partner for reducing execution time of the application from 2 hours to less than a minute (reduction of execution time achieved using inverted indexing of SOLR).
- IT Analyst, Caterpillar India Pvt Ltd.

10/2012 to 10/2014

- Developed mine control software Minestar, used for controlling and monitoring entire operations in a mine site.
 Worked on modules: Fleet provides real-time machine tracking and monitoring, Command which allows remote control of vehicles, Health event-based machine condition monitoring system. Used Java, Spring, Hibernate,
 Oracle11g and MSSQL
- Initiated and developed a POC: Route Congestion Identifier which lets us find out the routes in the mine site which
 are most congested, thereby allowing the mine- controller to redirect trucks. Used Java, Hadoop MapReduce, Apache
 Oozie and Sqoop.
- o Presented with Remarkable Results Award for my efforts in Minestar project.

Assistant Systems Engineer, Tata Consultancy Services

02/2011 to 09/2012

- Developed a high availability SOA based message processing middleware system, which processes huge volumes of data from different airlines and provides a single processing channel for relevant airline rules. – used Java, IBM MQ, MB, WPS, SOAP Web Services and Oracle 11g.
- Received Top Performer Award during initial training process.